Contact

720-412-1149 (Mobile) glendenning.levi@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/leviglendenning (LinkedIn) github.com/LeviG68 (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Customer Service Microsoft Excel Leadership

Levi Glendenning

Junior Full stack developer looking for a career in web development. Aurora, Colorado

Summary

Seeker of knowledge & Business graduate who currently has his sights set on a full-time web development position. Experienced in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, React, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Passport, Mongoose, cheerio, test driven development, and Handlebars. Additionally, 10 years plus of knowledge in logistics, transportation, and supply chain.

When not working I am outside enjoying Colorado wilderness either hiking or biking, woodworking or camping with my family.

Experience

PepsiCo Sr.Route Logistics Analyst January 2013 - Present Denver, Colorado

Multi Billion \$ soda company the Specialized Dispatch Operations (SDO) is supply chain analytics for cost savings and increased efficiencies by using flex dispatching (fewest driver and trucks).

Managed over 20 locations across the U.S working for cost reduction.

Daily communications with Territory Sales Manager / Delivery Supervisors regarding resources and routing solutions, while maintaining a manifest compliance of 90% Bulk / 80% Bay and ensuring lowest costs solutions.

Executed a pilot program for new software within the department, provided feedback on errors, usability, future enhancements.

Excellent team player willing to collaborate on innovative ideas to overcome issues and, always work toward best practices for solutions.

Working in conjunction with locations on a constant review on route performance both in planning and execution of customer requirement and locations planned P & L.

FedEx Express

RTD Driver

June 2010 - August 2013 (3 years 3 months)

Regional Transport Driver, pre and post trip all loads to and from FedEx Denver ramp, do en route safety checks of truck and cargo, hook and unhook all trailer to/from tractors, load and unload freight at needed, and safely transport all loads to/from Denver ramp area.

FedEx Express

Handler/Coordinator

June 2010 - August 2013 (3 years 3 months)

Work as a group to sort between fifteen and twenty thousand packages per night, maintaining less than 5% miss-sort per night.

Responsible for final inspection and weight of containers prior to loading onto flights.

Finishing management training within FedEx Express program.

Operated tractor-trailer combinations, perform daily pre-trip safety inspections Review all paperwork including any hazardous materials, load and secure all freight.

Communicated with dispatch with any delays, arrivals and traffic delays.

Currently completing Commercial Drivers Licenses class A with endorsements, along with yard holster training.

Watkins Shepard Trucking Regional Dispatch Manager April 2008 - March 2010 (2 years)

Missoula, Montana Area

Promoted from Assistant Dispatch Manager, promoted from Fleet Manager

Coordinated logistics and resolved all issues related to 80+ delivery drivers within a 3-state territory.

Achieved a 95% or higher on-time delivery average for 20+ accounts, including the Home Depot, Pier 1 Imports, Anheuser Busch, E.&J. Gallo Winery and General Mills.

Coached drivers to meet or exceed company objectives; advised employees on ways to minimize equipment idle time while meeting fuel compliance and response time standards.

Monitored daily reports to proactively address any issues involving freight, equipment, drivers and delivery times; hedged emergency situations by anticipating and solving problems rapidly.

Liaison between company management, drivers, shop workers, terminal managers and clients; actively communicated to keep all parties informed of changes in circumstances and schedules.

Collaborated and maintained constant communication with territory account manager to ensure maximum usage of company resources at all times.

Western States Equipment
Rental Coordinator
June 2005 - January 2008 (2 years 8 months)
Missoula, Montana Area

procedures.

Made key decisions and managed multiple projects simultaneously while maintaining over 100 customer accounts and overseeing day-to-day operations at The Cat Rental Store.

Led team of 6 to achieve goal of \$2M in sales each year; expanded sales by 5% year-over-year.

Assessed the needs of independent customers, subcontractors and contractors to recommend the best equipment and rental plan to meet their needs within their budget; developed estimates and frequently negotiated costs and contract terms to create win-win situations with clients.

Regularly implemented new means of decreasing employee downtime and reducing operational expenses while adhering to company policies and

Coordinated with mechanics and customers over the scope and value of work done to rental equipment with little disruptions to customer's rental period.

Page 3 of 4

Education

University of Denver
Center for Professional Development, Full Stack Web
Development · (2018 - 2018)

Galvanize Inc

Python Language workshop, Data science Workshops · (2016 - 2016)

The University of Montana

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration; Management and Marketing · (2000 - 2005)